이곳 에드워드 공군 기지에서는
발사 준비가 한창입니다
The countdown is underway
here at Edwards air force base.
알트만 에어로다이너믹스사에서
개발한 신형 실험용 로켓 비행기가
The new experimental rocket plane
which was developed by
Altman aerodynamics
태평양 표준시로 내일 아침
7시 30분에 발사될 예정입니다
is scheduled to launch tomorrow
morning at 7:30 Pacific time.
4명의 승무원을 지휘할 사람은
우리에게도 친숙한 인물입니다
The four man crew will be lead
by a familiar face.
바로 우주 비행사이자 민간인
시험 비행 조종사인 스티븐 와그너 씨죠
Astronaut and civilian test pilot
Steven Wagner.
와그너 씨는 4년 전 우주선이
대기권에 재진입하는 동안
Wagner became a national hero
four years ago
대담하게 비상 착륙에 성공함으로써
when he made a courageous
emergency landing
국가적인 영웅이 되었습니다
in the space shuttle during reentry.
그 국가적인 영웅이
바로 내 거실에 와 있네요
A national hero
in my very own living room.
하지만 당신에게는 절대
영웅이 되지 못하겠지?
But I'll never be a hero to you, will I?
한때는 그랬죠
You were once.
이게 그거야?
Is this it?
'잠자리에서 -
조앤 라펠슨의 자서전'이라
Between the sheets:
The Joanne Raphelson story.
읽어 볼래요?
자기 얘기는 5장(章)에 나와요
You want to read it?
You're chapter five.
- 몇 장이나 되는데?
- 15장요
- How many chapters are there?
- 15.
이런, 당신 바쁜 여자였군, 조앤
Wow, you've been a busy girl, Joanne.
그건 겨우 시리즈 첫 편일 뿐이에요
And that's only volume one.
정말 상세히 써 놨겠지?
You really went into detail?
내 편집장이 그렇게 고집하더라고요
외설적일수록 더 좋다나
My editor insisted on it.
The juicier, the better.
그래서 자길 부른 거예요, 스티브
자기를 놀라게 하긴 싫었거든요
That's why I called you, Steve.
I didn't want you to be surprised.
고맙군, 조앤
I appreciate that, Joanne.
정말 고마워
I really do.
그래, 이 책을 본 사람이
혹시 또 있나?
So has anyone seen
this new version yet?
아직은 없어요
Not yet.
언제 넘길 건데?
When do you hand it in?
다음 주에요
아직 교정 중이거든요
Next week.
I'm still proofreading it.
건배
Cheers.
올리브, 체리, 양파군요
이 칵테일 이름이 뭐죠?
An olive, a cherry, and an onion.
What do you call this?
'우주 유영'이라고 부르지
내가 직접 만든 거야
A spacewalk. It's my own recipe.
멋진 이름이네요
It's a good name.
내가 날고 있는 것 같아요
Feel like I'm flying.
그거 읽어 보시게요?
So do you want to read it?
그럴 생각으로 여기 온 거지만...
I plan to.
That's why I'm here but...
맘을 바꿨어
I've changed my mind.
난 15년이나 시험 비행 조종을 해 왔어
Hell, I've been a test pilot for 15 years.
한 번은 우주선을 바다에
착륙시킨 적도 있지
I once landed a space shuttle
in the ocean.
5장에 뭐라고 쓰여 있든
내가 알아서 할 수 있을 거야
I think I can handle
whatever's in chapter five.
그러니 갖다 주라고
제대로 한번 날 공격해 봐
So hand it in.
Hit me with your best shot.
고마워요, 스티브
Thank you, Steve.
스티븐 씨, 상원에 출마할 생각을
하고 계시다는 소문이 있던데요
Sir, there's a rumor you might be
considering a run for senate.
모르겠습니다
워싱턴에 가 본 적이 있는데
I don't know.
I've been to Washington.
자기 좀 봐요 / 거기보다는
우주가 더 편안하게 느껴집니다
- Look at you.
- I think I'm a lot safer in outer space.
아주 귀여운데요
Damn, you're cute.
사실은, 이번 임무 후에 진지하게
제 진로를 고민할 예정입니다
Seriously, after this mission, I'm going to
sit down and review my options.
하지만 이건 말씀드릴 수 있습니다
But I will say this.
제가 의원 출마를 선택한다면
평소와 같은 자세로 임할 겁니다
If I choose to run for public office,
I'll treat it like any other mission.
전 최선을 다할 것이고
반드시 이길 겁니다
I will fully commit and I will win.
실패란 있을 수 없습니다
Failure is not an option.
자막제작 - NSC 자막팀
(http://club.nate.com/tsm)
MONK Season 4 Epi. 14
Mr. Monk and the Astronaut
토니 샬롭
(에이드리안 몽크 役)
트레일러 하워드
(나탈리 티거 役)
제이슨 그레이 스탠포드
(랜달 디셔 경위 役)
테드 리바인
(리랜드 스토틀마이어 경감 役)
딕테이션
김철균(kim1047@nate.com)
싱크편집
윤선영(seedyun@nate.com)
한글번역
신성아(elley@nate.com)
번역수정
홍관호(kwanho_hong@nate.com)
한글교정
임재영(dreamimage@nate.com)
ORIGINAL AIR DATE ON USA: 2006/03/03
안녕하세요, 라펠슨 양
Hello, Miss Raphelson.
라펠슨 양, 밖에 차가 있더군요
Miss Raphelson, I see your car.
라펠슨 양?
Miss Raphelson?
맙소사!
Madre de dios!
맙소사, 라펠슨 양!
Madre de dios, Miss Raphelson!
하나님 아버지!
Madre de dios!
강연의 날이라뇨?
(Career day : 다양한 직업에 종사하는
사람들을 초청하여 소개하는 학교 행사)
Career day.
나더러 뭘 말하라고요?
(Career day : 다양한 직업에 종사하는
사람들을 초청하여 소개하는 학교 행사)
What would I talk about?
몽크 씨의 직업요. 일 말이에요
(Career day : 다양한 직업에 종사하는
사람들을 초청하여 소개하는 학교 행사)
Your career. Your job.
부탁이에요, 몽크 씨
줄리에게 큰 의미가 될 거예요
Oh, come on, Mr. Monk.
It would mean so much to Julie.
그렇겠지만, 난 못해요
Yeah. I can't do it.
미안해요. 난 사람들 앞에서
연설 못한다고요
I'm sorry. I can't speak in public.
잠깐만요. 그건 사실이 아니죠
See, that's not true.
제가 몽크 씨 비서로 처음 일할 때
Remember when I first
started working for you
몽크 씨가 각종 공포증 목록을
적어 주신 거 기억하시죠?
and you made that list
of all your fears and phobias.
103가지나 됐지만
연설은 목록에 없었어요
There were 103 things.
Public speaking wasn't one of them.
사실은 목록에 안 적은 게
몇 개 있었어요
Actually, there were a couple of things
that I didn't mention.
날 이상한 사람으로 생각할까 봐요
I didn't want you to think I was weird.
경감님께 부탁하지그래요?
Why don't you ask the captain?
그게 뭐든, 물어봐 줘서 고맙지만
난 못합니다
Whatever it is, thank you for asking,
but I can't do it.
어쨌든 다행이군
Luckyful though, dawg.
가정부는 자기 키를 갖고 있어요
2주에 한 번씩 왔는데
The housekeeper has her own key.
She comes in every other week.
두 시간 전에 여기에서
시체를 발견했다는군요
She found the body
right here a couple hours ago.
피해자 이름은... 조앤 라펠슨이고요
36세, 전직 라스베가스 쇼걸입니다
Her name is, uh, Joanne Raphelson.
36. Former Vegas showgirl.
검시관이 방금 시체를 실어 갔고요
And the coroner just took the body.
검시관 말로는
죽은 지 5일 됐다니까...
Said she's been dead for five days.
So that makes it, uh...
- 수요일 아침이네요
- 수요일이라
- Wednesday morning.
- Wednesday.
잠깐만요, 우린 여기 왜 온 거예요?
자살했다잖아요. 그렇죠?
Excuse me. Why are we here?
She killed herself, right?
그럴지도 모르죠
확실하진 않아요
Uh, maybe.
I'm not sure.
내가 몇 가지 미심쩍은 걸 발견했는데
자네가 좀 봐줬으면 해
I noticed a few things.
I wanted to run them by you.
뉴욕에 있는 출판사에서 보낸
편지를 발견했네
Found a letter from a publisher
in New York.
피해자가 책을
출판하려던 참이었더군
She was about to have
a book published.
'잠자리에서 - 조앤 라펠슨의 자서전'
이라는 제목의 회고록이야
A memoir called, "Between the sheets:
The Joanne Raphelson story."
잠자리...
Between the...
아, 네. 알겠어요
Oh, yeah. I get it.
게다가 아직 예금하지 않은
5만 달러짜리 수표도 발견했어
And a check for 50 grand,
which she has not deposited.
목을 매서 자살하기엔
아주 이상한 때지?
Pretty weird time to hang yourself, huh?
훌륭하십니다, 경감님
Good work, sir.
그렇게 놀란 척할 필요 없네, 랜디
You don't have to sound
so surprised, Randy.
아, 놀란 게 아니라요
Oh, I'm not surprised.
압도당한 겁니다
Awestruck.
- 감명 받은 거라고요
- 그러지 마
- Awestruck.
- Well, don't be.
명령일세 / 감명 받지
말라고 명령하시는 거예요?
And that's an order. / You're ordering
me not to be awestruck?
맞아. 저쪽에 가 있게
감명 받지도 말고
That's right. Stand over there
and don't be awestruck.
네
Sir.
다른 건요?
Anything else?
아, 컴퓨터가 없어진 것 같아
Uh, yeah. Looks like
her computer's missing.
멀티탭이랑 프린터는 있는데
컴퓨터가 없어
There's a power strip with a surge protector,
a printer, and no computer.
잠시만요, 경감님
Excuse me, sir.
죄송합니다. 제 평생
명령에 불복종한 적은 없지만
Sorry. I've never disobeyed
an order in my life.
정말 훌륭하십니다
아주 멋져요
It's really good work.
It's awesome.
랜디, 밖에 나가서
탐문 수사나 하지 그러나?
Randy, why don't you go outside
and talk to the neighbors?
네, 경감님
Yes, sir.
정말 멋져요
It's awesome.
그럼 내 생각이 맞은 건가?
뭔가 좀 이상하지?
So am I right?
Something's not kosher?
피해자의 운전면허증이네요
It's her driver's license.
그 걸상 높이가
얼마나 되는 것 같아요?
How tall do you think that stool is?
한 45cm 정도요
About 18 inches.
밧줄 높이는 바닥에서
230cm 정도예요
The rope's 7'6".
면허증에 적힌 걸 봐서는
피해자는 165cm밖에 안 돼요
But according to her license,
she's only 5'5".
제가 165cm예요
I'm 5'5".
올라가 보세요
Step up.
경감님이 맞아요
You're right.
뭔가 이상하네요
It doesn't add up.
여기에서 얼마나 사셨죠?
So how long have you lived here?
15년요. 14년인가?
저기요...
15 years. Maybe 14.
You know what?
우리 어머니가 아실 겁니다
돌아오면 물어보세요
My old lady would know that.
You can ask her when she gets back.
그분이 술에 취하지 않았다면요
If she's sober.
저기, 이거 하나 드릴까요?
Hey, you want one of these?
복숭아예요. 아주 완벽한 과일이죠
Nectarines. They're the perfect fruit.
그러죠 / 받으세요
Okay. / There you go.
왜 또 차고 문이 열려 있는 거야?
Now why is the garage door
open again?
베니, 내가 뭐라고 했지?
Benny, what'd I tell you about this?
- 제가 그런 게 아니에요
- 그러셔? 그럼 누군데?
- I didn't open it.
- Really. Well, then who did?
도나가 그랬을지도 모르죠
그런 생각은 안 해 보셨어요?
Maybe Donna did it.
You ever think of that?
그거 아니? 네 여동생은
크레용 상자도 못 열어
You know what? Your sister
couldn't open up a box of crayons.
쟤는 6살이거든요
She's six years old, for god.
케인 씨, 몇 가지 더 여쭙겠습니다
Mr. Cain, I just have a few more questions.
라펠슨 양을 얼마나 아시나요?
How well did you know Ms. Raphelson?
원하는 만큼은 알지 못하죠
무슨 뜻인지 아시려나
Not as well as I wanted to,
if you get my drift.
그 여자 정말 섹시했잖아요
Hey, she was hot.
아까워라
What a waste.
지난주에 라펠슨 양을
찾아온 사람이 있었나요?
Did she have any visitors last week?
화요일이나 수요일에요?
Say Tuesday or Wednesday?
아뇨, 아무도 없었어요
No. Nobody. Nobody.
제가 기억하는 한은 없었어요
Not as far as I recall anyway.
이런, 또야...?
헥터가 나가잖아!
Oh, for, not a...
Hector's out!
베니, 개 좀 데리고 와 주겠니?
Benny, could you,
go get your dog, please.
- 제가 왜 그래야 하는데요?
- 네가 차고를 열어 놨으니까 그렇지
- Why should I?
- Because you opened up the garage.
어이, 똑똑이
이분은 경찰이야. 그렇지?
Hey, smart guy.
This is a police officer, right?
이분한테 널 잡아가라고 할 수도 있어
I could have him lock you up.
잘 생각해 봐라
You think about that.
- 어떤가?
- 경감님
- How's it going?
- Captain.
이분은 대럴 케인 씨예요
This is, uh, Darrel Cain.
케인 씨, 여기는 리랜드 스토틀마이어 경감님
나탈리 티거 씨, 에이드리안 몽크 씨예요
Darrel Cain, captain Leland Stottlemeyer.
Natalie Teeger. Adrian Monk.
안녕하세요
Hi.
케인 씨는 지난주에 집에 있었는데
아무것도 못 봤다고 합니다 / 잠깐만...
Mr. Cain says he was home last week.
But he didn't see anything. / Excuse me.
그 상자에 쓰여 있는 주소는
조앤 라펠슨으로 되어 있는데요
That box is addressed
to Joanne Raphelson.
맞아요. 조앤네 현관에 있더군요
Yeah. It was on her porch.
조앤이 죽었다기에
갖는 사람이 임자라고 생각했죠
Well, I'd heard she died.
I figured it was up for grabs.
남의 집 현관에 있는
우편물을 가져가시면 안 되죠
You can't just take mail
from somebody's porch.
과일은 괜찮아요
Yeah, you can if it's fruit.
과일은 썩으니까 법에
저촉되지 않는다고요
Law doesn't apply to fruit
because it's perishable.
사실, 과일도 법에 저촉됩니다
Actually, sir,
the law does apply to fruit.
자네도 먹고 있는 건가?
Are you eating one?
아뇨. 다시 돌려놓으려 했었어요
No. I was just putting that back.
- 경감님, 통화 기록을 원하셨죠?
- 그래
Captain, you wanted to see
her phone record. / Yeah.
월요일이나 화요일에는
통화 기록이 없네요?
No calls at all on Tuesday or Monday?
마지막 통화는
토요일 새벽 2시 5분에 걸었군
Last call she made was
Saturday morning at 2:05 A.M.
안녕하세요, 저는 샌프란시스코 경찰국의
리랜드 스토틀마이어 경감입니다
Hello. This is captain Leland Stottlemeyer,
San Francisco police.
누구시죠?
Who's this?
스토틀마이어 경감님이시죠?
Captain Stottlemeyer?
네. 맞습니다
Yeah. Hey.
- 지금 바쁘신가요?
- 아뇨, 아닙니다
- Is this a bad time?
- Oh. No. No.
친구들 몇 명이 제게 조촐한 파티를
열어 주는 중이죠. 일종의 전통입니다
Some friends are throwing me
a little party. It's sort of a tradition.
우주선 승선을 축하합니다
Congratulations on your flight.
아, 4년 전 비상 착륙 하신 것도
축하합니다
Hey, and, uh, congratulations
on that crash landing four years ago.
피겨 스케이팅 선수와 결혼하신 것도요
Oh, and, uh, marrying the figure skater.
그래요, 와그너 씨 일생 전부를
축하해야겠군요
Yeah, congratulations on your
whole damn life.
여기는 디셔 경위, 나탈리 티거 씨
그리고 에이드리안 몽크 씨입니다
This is lieutenant Disher,
Natalie Teeger, and Adrian Monk.
몽크 씨, 댁을 알아요
Monk. I know that name.
형사셨죠
You're the detective.
그만두셨고요
The one who quit.
정, 정확히는 그만둔 게 아닙니다
I, I, I didn't quit, exactly.
그게... 휴직을 한 겁니다
It was, it was a leave of absence.
부끄러워하실 필요 없습니다, 몽크 씨
It's nothing to be ashamed of, Mr. Monk.
어떤 사람들은 압박을
견디지 못하죠
Some people just can't
handle the pressure.
난 그만둔 게 아닙니다
I didn't quit.
와그너 씨, 죄송해요
Mr. Wagner, I'm sorry.
제 딸이 와그너 씨에 대한
과제물을 쓰고 있거든요
My daughter just wrote
a school paper about you.
잘됐네요. 홍보가
많이 될수록 저야 좋죠
Good. I need all the P.R. I can get.
와그너 씨를 만났다는 걸 딸아이가
안 믿을 텐데, 사진 좀 찍어도 될까요?
She's not gonna believe that I met you.
Do you mind if I take a picture?
- 그러시죠
- 고마워요
- Not at all.
- Thank you.
나... 난 포기하지 않았어요
그만두지 않았다고요
I'm not, I'm not a quitter.
I didn't quit.
- 그럴 만한 사정이 있었어요
- 사정이야 항상 있죠
- There were extenuating circumstances.
- There always are.
성공의 비결은 그런 사정들에
굴복하지 않는 것입니다
The trick is not to let them stop us.
경감님, 긴히 얘기할 게 있다고 하셨죠
Captain, you said it was important.
아, 그렇죠...
Oh, yeah. Um...
조앤 라펠슨이란 여자를 아십니까?
Do you know a woman named
Joanne Raphelson?
조앤이 죽었군요. 그렇죠?
She's dead, isn't she?
결국 그랬군요
She finally did it.
놀라지 않으시네요
You're not surprised.
조앤은 요 몇 달 동안 우울증에
빠져 있었어요. 실은 몇 년 됐죠
Joanne's been depressed for months.
For years, really.
책을 출판하려던 참이었는데
뭔가 잘 안 됐나 봐요
She was about to have a book published
but somehow that made it worse.
몽크 씨, 제가 말씀드린 것처럼
어떤 사람들은 압박을 견디지 못한답니다
Like I was saying, Mr. Monk,
some people just can't handle the pressure.
난 심리적 문제 때문에
면직이 된 거라고요
It was a psychological discharge,
for god's sake.
- 일시적인 조치였을 뿐이에요
- 복직할 예정이고요
- It was only temporary.
- I plan on being reinstated.
- 지금은 많이 좋아졌어요
- 라펠슨 양과는 어떤 사이셨나요?
- He's so much better.
- How well did you know her?
애인 사이였죠
Intimately.
- 마지막으로 만나신 게 언제입니까?
- 5년 전입니다
- When was the last time you saw her?
- Five years ago.
아뇨, 잠깐만요. 지난주에
그쪽한테 전화했던데요
No, wait, she called you
on the phone last week.
맞습니다. 일 년에 한두 번씩은
저에게 전화합니다
That's true.
She calls me once or twice a year
외롭거나, 우울하거나, 취했거나
가끔은 세 가지 다 그럴 때요
when she's lonely, depressed,
or drunk, and sometimes all three.
스티븐?
Steven?
- 여보, 우리 케이크를 잘라야 해
- 저기, 와그너 씨
- Honey, we're cutting the cake.
- Hey, look, uh,
얘긴 내일 마저 하셔도 됩니다
we could talk about this tomorrow, okay?
괜찮습니다, 경감님
아내와는 비밀이 없거든요
That's all right, captain.
I have no secrets from my wife.
여보, 이분들은 형사들이셔
Honey, these gentlemen are detectives.
조앤 라펠슨이 죽었대
Joanne Raphelson is dead.
어머, 저런. 불쌍한 아가씨
Oh, no. Poor girl.
전 실수를 했습니다, 경감님
5년 전에요
I made a mistake, captain.
Five years ago.
니콜도 다 알고 있어요
Nicole knows all about it.
니콜은 제게 정말 과분한 여자죠
I don't deserve this woman.
실례하지만, 부인
마시고 계신 게 뭐죠?
Excuse me, ma'am.
What is that you're drinking?
'우주 유영'이라고 해요
제 남편이 만들어낸 거죠
It's called a spacewalk.
My husband invented it.
그, 그건 올리브인가요?
Is, is that an olive?
양파하고 체리고요
And an onion and a cherry.
나름대로 유명하답니다
한 잔 드릴까요?
It's my claim to fame.
Would you like one?
아뇨, 고맙습니다
No, thank you.
와그너 씨, 비행에 관한 기사를 읽었는데
당신이 기지에 늦게 도착하는 바람에
Mr. Wagner, I was reading about
your flight and they said they
almost had to cancel the liftoff.
- 발사를 취소할 뻔했다더군요
- 사실입니다
- You were running late.
- That's true.
기지로 오던 중에 길을 잃었거든요
믿어지세요?
I got lost on my way to Edwards.
Can you believe it?
- 길을 잃었다고요?
- 다른 지름길로 가려고 하다가요
- You, you got lost?
- I tried a different short cut.
저는 땅에 있는 길보다는
하늘길이 더 익숙한가 봅니다
I, I, I guess I'm a better navigator
in the sky than I am on the highways.
- 의원님, 와 주셔서 고맙습니다
- 스티브
Congressman, glad you
could make it. / Steve.
어이, 자네 장래에 대해서는
언제 얘기 나눌 건가?
Hey, when are we gonna have
that talk about your future?
빠를수록 좋죠
The sooner, the better.
실례해도 될까요?
친구들이 기다리고 있어서요
Will you excuse us?
My friends are waiting.
- 나중에 다시 말씀 나누시죠
- 그럽시다
We can talk about this
some other time. / Absolutely.
- 좋습니다
- 만나서 반가웠어요
Great. / It was nice to meet you.
반가웠습니다
Nice to meet you.
저 남자 짓입니다
He's the guy.
- 누구 말인가?
- 저 우주 비행사요
- Who's the guy?
- The astronaut.
저 사람이 조앤을 죽였어요
He killed her.
조앤이 죽기 전에 누군가 그 여자 집에서
똑같은 칵테일을 만들어 줬어요
Somebody made that exact same drink
at Joanne Raphelson's house before she died.
몽크, 그건 불가능해
저 사람은 우주에 있었다고
Monk, it's not possible.
He was in space.
저 사람이 죽였다니까요
He did it.
지구 밖에 있었다니까, 몽크
Outer space, Monk.
TV에 나왔잖아
지구 궤도를 선회하고 있었다고
He was on TV.
He was orbiting the Earth.
인정하셔야겠네요
아주 완벽한 알리바이잖아요
Gotta admit, it's a pretty good alibi.
저, 저 사람이라니까
He, he's the guy.
몽크, 100번 중 99번은
난 자네 편이지만
Monk, 99 times out of 100,
I am in your corner.
이번만은 아닐세
스티브 와그너는 국가적인 영웅이야
But I just can't see it.
Steve Wagner is a national hero.
그건 맞아요, 몽크 씨
It's true, Mr. Monk.
타임지 표지를 장식한 인물이라고
He was on the cover of Time magazine.
- 사실, 그건 뉴스위크지였어요
- 사실, 둘 다였네
- Actually, it was Newsweek.
- Actually, it was both.
자, 차근차근 다시 살펴보자고
Now look, we need to tread carefully here.
첫 번째, 동기가 없잖아
아내는 불륜에 대해 다 알고 있었어
First off, there's no motive.
The wife knew about the affair.
- 많은 사람들이 알고 있었지
- 그냥 단순한 불륜이 아니었어요
- A lot of people did.
- It wasn't just the affair.
방금 뉴욕에 있는 조앤 라펠슨의
편집장과 얘기해 봤는데요
We just talked to Joanne Raphelson's
editor in New York.
조앤이 넘기기로 한 원고에 굉장히
충격적인 이야기가 포함되어 있었대요
She was about to hand in her next draft,
which contained a couple of real bombshells.
어떤 이야기? / 5년 전 옛 애인이
조앤을 때렸다는 이야기요
Like? / Like which of her ex-boyfriends
beat her up five years ago.
누군가 조앤을 병원에 입원시켰대요
Somebody put her in the hospital.
뇌진탕이었다죠. 그렇죠?
She had a concussion, right?
나탈리도 스티브 와그너가
관련됐다고 생각해요?
And you think Steve Wagner's involved?
전 믿을 수가 없네요
죄송해요, 몽크 씨
I just don't believe it.
I'm sorry, Mr. Monk.
와그너는 의원이 되고 싶어 해요
Look, Wagner wants to run for office.
그런 이야기는 와그너를
파멸시킬 거라고요
A story like that would bury him.
좋아. 동기를 알아냈다고 치자고
Okay. Maybe you found
a motive. Maybe.
그래도 변하는 건 없어
이유를 말해 주지
But it doesn't matter.
And I'll tell you why.
몽크, 자네의 용의자가
우주에 있었기 때문이야
Because your suspect, Monk,
was in outer space.
- 이 지구에 없었다고
- 진짜예요
- He wasn't on this planet.
- It's true.
- 줄리랑 제가 TV로 봤는걸요
- 전 세계가 다 봤지
- Julie and I watched it on television.
- The whole world was watching.
월요일에 출항해서
금요일에 도착했어
He took off on Monday
and he landed on Friday.
여기 사건 파일을 보게
Here's the case file.
검시관도 100% 확신하고 있어
The coroner is 100% sure.
조앤 라펠슨은 확실히 수요일 아침에
목을 매달아 질식해서 죽었대
He is certain that Joanne Raphelson
died of ligature strangulation
자네의 용의자가 우주에
있는 동안에 말이야
on Wednesday morning
while your man was in space.
뭔가 더 그럴듯한 설명이 가능한지
우리 잠시 생각해 보자고
Now maybe we should take a minute
and see if we can think of a better alibi.
- 정말 확실한 알리바이군요
- 그렇지
- It's a pretty good alibi.
- Yeah.
체내에 수면제 성분이 있었다고요?
She had drugs in her system?
Barbiturates.
네. 검시관 말로는 몇 알 먹었답니다
그런데 효과가 없자
Yeah, coroner says she took some pills.
They didn't work.
차선책으로 목을 매단 거죠
흔한 일입니다
She went to plan B and dangled herself.
It happens all the time.
하지만 경감님도 사건 현장이
뭔가 이상하다고 하셨잖아요
But you said yourself
the crime scene didn't look kosher.
몽크, 난 살인 사건일지 모른다는 거였지
와그너가 범인이라는 건 아니었어
Monk, what I'm saying is it might be murder,
but it wasn't him.
경감님
Captain.
- 몽크 선배 말이 맞는 것 같습니다
- 고맙네. 구원병이 와 줬군
- I think Monk's right.
- Thank you. Reinforcements.
와그너가 어떻게 했는지
알 것 같아요
I think I know how Wagner did it.
자, 이게 우주선이에요
Okay. This is the ship.
이 지구본이 지구를
표현한 거라고 가정하죠
And let's pretend this globe
represents the Earth.
그 지구본은 지구를 표현한 게 맞아
That's a globe.
It does represent the Earth.
그렇죠
Right.
자, 이렇게 된 거예요
Okay. Here's what happened.
처음 부분은 간단해요
우주선이 출발했죠
First part was easy.
He takes off.
샌프란시스코 위를 지나가고 있을 때
와그너는 탈출선을 작동시킨 거예요
As he passes over San Francisco,
he activates the escape pod.
그게, 잠깐, 잠깐만
Well, wait. Uh, wait.
그 우주선에 탈출선이 있었어?
Uh, was, was there
an escape pod on the ship?
아뇨. 공식적으로는 아니지만
No. Not officially.
와그너가 몰래 들여놨을 거예요
But I think he smuggled one on.
그럼 그 탈출선을 와그너가
어디서 구했다는 거예요?
And where did he get it,
the escape pod?
- 만들었겠죠
- 그래. 자기 지하실에 있는 도구로 말이지
- He built it.
- Yeah. Out of a kit in his basement.
재주가 좋은 사람이잖아요
어쨌든...
He's resourceful.
Anyway....
지구로 돌아온 후
splashdown.
탈출선에서 나와 조앤의
집으로 가서 조앤을 죽인 후
He climbs out of the pod,
makes his way to her house,
다시 탈출선으로 돌아가서 엔진을
켠 다음에 우주로 돌아간 거죠
kills her, climbs back onto the pod,
fires up the engines, back in space.
고맙네, 랜디
Thank you, Randy.
- 단지 이론일 뿐이에요
- 난 그렇게 생각하지 않아
- It's just a theory.
- I don't think so.
내가 이론에 대해서는
좀 아는데 말이야...
No. I've heard theories before and, uh,
자네 말처럼 황당한 건
이론이라고 안 해
they don't sound like that.
그 사람이에요
It's him.
스티브 와그너요
It's Steve Wagner.
여보세요?
Hello?
네
Yes.
정말요?
Really?
오, 정말 멋지네요
Oh, that's wonderful.
내일 아침 10시예요
Uh, tomorrow morning at 10 A.M.
애들이 정말 좋아할 거예요
Oh, the kids are gonna be so thrilled.
좋아요, 멋지네요. 그때 봐요
Okay, great. I'll see you then.
스티브 와그너가 강연의 날에
줄리의 학교에서 연설하기로 했어요
Steve Wagner is speaking
at Julie's school for career day.
잠깐만요. 그 사람을 초대했어요?
Wait, you invited him?
네. 어젯밤 거기서 나올 때
그 사람의 홍보 직원을 만났거든요
Yeah. I met his PR person last night
as we were leaving.
나탈리, 그자는 자기
옛 애인을 죽인 남자예요
Natalie, he killed his ex-girlfriend.
몽크, 자네도 가는 게 좋겠군
Monk, maybe you should go, too.
와그너가 관련됐다고 생각한다면
그 친구를 떠볼 기회가 될 거야
You think the guy's involved,
it'll give you a chance to feel him out.
좋아요
알았어요. 나도 가죠
Fine.
Okay. I'll do it.
두 분 다 오신다고요?
You're both coming?
올해의 학부모는 내 차지네
I'm gonna be class mom of the year.
너희 나이 때에
난 보이 스카우트였단다
When I was your age,
I was a boy scout.
보이 스카우트의 표어를 아는 사람?
Who here knows the boy scout motto?
준비해라!
Be prepared.
맞아
그 표어가 내 인생을 구했지
That's right.
And that motto saved my life.
착륙 장치에 문제가 생겼을 때
난 준비된 상태였으니까 말이야
Because when the landing gear
didn't come down, I was prepared.
내가 뭘 해야 하는지 알았지
I knew what I had to do.
난 플로리다를 지나서...
안녕, 플로리다
I went around Florida.
Good-bye, Florida.
루이지애나를 넘어 여기 멕시코 만에
동체 착륙으로 우주선을 세웠단다
Over Louisiana. And landed
the space shuttle here in the gulf of Mexico
with a great bigbelly flop.
- 무섭지 않았어요?
- 아니, 무섭다기보다는
- And you weren't even scared?
- No, I wasn't scared.
끔찍하게 두려웠지!
I was terrified!
사람들은 날 영웅이라 불렀지만
People called me a hero.
누구든 그렇게 할 수 있단다
But anyone, anybody could've done that.
너, 너
You or you,
그리고 너, 너...
or you or you or...
나탈리 씨와 선생님도 말이야
you or you.
용기를 낸다는 건 두려움을 극복하고
그걸 해낸다는 뜻이란다
Being brave is being afraid of something
but doing it anyway.
다음엔 뭘 하실 건데요?
What are you gonna do next?
내일은 공군을 위해 FA-22 랩터라는
신형 제트기를 시험 비행할 거야
Well, tomorrow, I'm testing a brand-new jet
for the air force called the FA-22 raptor.
세계에서 가장 진보적인 전투기지
It's the most advanced fighter
in the world.
그 제트기는 소리의 속도보다 빠르단다
She's faster than the speed of sound.
그러니 내일 하늘에서 큰 굉음이 들린다면
내가 너희에게 인사하는 거야
So if you hear a big boom in the sky
tomorrow, that's me saying hello, kids.
가기 전에 선물을 주마
Before I go,
너희에게 주려고 스티브 와그너의
레이저 포인터를 가지고 왔단다
I brought some official Steve Wagner
laser pointers for all you kids.
여기 있다
하나씩 가지고 뒤로 넘기렴
Here you go.
Take one, pass them back.
아주 즐거운 시간이었다
Well, I had a great time.
그리고 기억하거라. 이 스티브 와그너는
너희가 어떻게 하길 원한다고?
And remember, what does
Steve Wagner want you to do?
목표를 높게 가져라!
Aim high.
자
Right there.
정말 고마워요, 와그너 씨
정말 멋지죠, 여러분?
Thank you so much, Mr. Wagner.
Wasn't he great?
모두 박수 칩시다
Let's give him a hand.
고마워요
Thank you.
자, 줄리의 다음 초청 손님은
내 고용주이기도 한 에이드리안 몽크 씨예요
Okay, so Julie's next guest is
Mr. Adrian Monk, who's also my boss.
그러니 모두들 경청하세요
So, everybody, be extra nice.
몽크 씨는 형사가 되는 게
어떤 건지 말씀해 주실 거예요
He's going to talk about what it's like
to be a police detective.
안녕
Hi.
안녕, 나는...
Hi, I'm...
나는...
I'm, um...
I'm...
놔두세요
Leave it.
나는...
I'm, uh...
에이드리안 몽크란다
I'm Adrian Monk.
나중에 커서 형사가
되고 싶은 사람 있니?
Who wants to be a detective
when they grow up?
넌 어때?
What about you?
아냐?
No?
네 줄에 있는 사람 모두
손을 들었거든
Everybody in your row
has their hand up.
너도 손을 든다면...
If you put your hand up...
완벽한 줄이 될 텐데
it would be a perfect row.
손 들거라!
Put your hand up!
총은 어디 있어요?
Where's your gun?
그게, 난...
Um, I, uh,
가지고 있지 않단다
I don't have, I don't have one.
신경 쇠약에 걸려서
가지고 다니지 못하는 거겠죠
You can't carry one
'cause you had a breakdown.
아, 그래, 어...
Oh, well, uh...
줄리가 그러는데 아저씨는
우유를 무서워한다면서요?
Julie says you're afraid of milk.
누구나 무서워하는 게
하나쯤 있지 않니?
Well, everybody's afraid
of something, right?
줄리는 아저씨가 모든 걸 다
무서워한다고 했어요
Julie said you're afraid of everything.
몽크 아저씨, 전 정말...
Mr. Monk, I really, I'm...
진짜 살인범을 잡아 보신 적이 있어요?
Have you ever caught a real killer?
아, 그래...
Oh, yes. Oh...
맞아. 많은 살인범을 잡았지
Yes, I've caught a lot of killers.
어떤 살인범들은 아주 영리하단다
Some killers are very smart.
그리고 어떤 이들은
권력도 아주 막강하지
And some are very powerful.
어떤 이들은 유명하기까지 하단다
자기는 절대 잡히지 않을 거라 생각하지
Some are even famous.
They don't think they will ever be caught.
하지만 결국엔
But in the end,
살인범들은 항상 잡히지
they, they're always caught.
왜 그런지 말해 주마
And I'll tell you why.
경찰도 실수를 할 수 있기 때문이야
Because the police can make mistakes.
나도 항상 실수를 한단다
I make mistakes all the time.
하지만, 음... 하지만...
But, uh, but...
그게, 살인범은...
see, a killer has to be, uh...
살인범은 완벽해야 하거든
하지만, 음...
A killer has to be perfect.
And, uh...
완벽한 사람은 없단다
nobody's perfect.
경찰은 기원전 200년에
고대 로마에서 처음 생겼단다
The first police officers appeared
in Ancient Rome in 200 B.C.
'백부장(百夫長)'이라는
명칭으로 불렸는데
They were called centurions.
많은 면에서 현대의 경찰들과
비슷했단다
In many ways, they were like
our modern police force.
그 사람들이 하는 일은...
It was their job to, to...
법을 집행하고...
to enforce laws and to...
치안을 유지하는 거였지
to maintain order.
그곳에 선발되기 위해선...
They were, uh,
chosen for their...
충성심과 용기가 있어야 했단다
their loyalty and their courage.
여기요, 몽크 씨
Here, Mr. Monk.
이거 마셔요. 괜찮아요?
Drink that.
Are you okay?
정말 멋진 강연이었어요
That was a good, good speech.
아이들이 많은 걸 배웠을 거예요
I think the kids learned a lot.
아직도 웃고 있어요?
Are they still laughing?
금방 멈출 거예요
They'll have to stop soon.
수업 시간이 거의 끝났거든요
The period's almost over.
난 꼭...
I am such a...
- 그거 뭐라고 하죠?
- 겁쟁이요
- What do you call it?
- Wuss.
아뇨, 몽크 씨
몽크 씨는 겁쟁이가 아니에요
No, Mr. Monk, you are not a wuss.
난 인간이 아니에요
나도 알아요
Well, I'm not a man.
I know that.
난 돌연변이죠
I'm a mutant.
반은 인간이고 반은 겁쟁이인
짬뽕 인간이에요
I'm half man, half wuss.
I'm a muss.
우리 용감한 백부장님, 여기 계셨군요
강연 참 좋았어요
Here you are. Our brave centurion.
I liked your speech.
특히 마지막에 그 깜찍한 춤이요
Especially the little dance number
at the end.
그 레이저 포인터들은 아주
위험할 수도 있어요
Those laser pointers
can be very dangerous.
네, 정말 위협적이죠. 몽크 씨가 저를
조사하고 계시다는 걸 들었어요
Yeah. They're a real menace.
I hear you've been checking up on me.
조앤의 가족과 편집장에게 전화하며
제 뒤를 캐고 계시던데
Calling Joanne's family.
Her publisher. Turning over rocks.
할 말이 있다면 지금 하시죠
인간 대 돌연변이로요
If you want to talk to me,
let's talk right now, man to muss.
- 그 여자를 때렸나요?
- 누굴요?
- Did you hit her?
- Hit who?
조앤요. 병원에서 깨어날 정도로
심하게 때리지 않았나요?
Joanne. Did you hit her so hard
that she woke up in the hospital?
그만 하시죠, 몽크 씨
그건 중상모략입니다
I wouldn't repeat that, Mr. Monk.
That's slander.
게다가 그걸 누가 믿겠습니까?
Besides, who would believe it?
그래서 조앤을 죽인 거죠?
That's why you killed her, isn't it?
조앤이 그 사실을
출판하려고 했으니까요
Because she was about to go public.
댁에 대해서 진실을 말하려 했던 거죠
She was about to tell the truth
about you.
불쌍한 양반. 당신 같은 사람이
있다니 믿을 수가 없군요
You're a sad little man. I can't believe
you and I breathe the same air.
난 우주선에 있었어요, 몽크 씨
I was on a space ship, Mr. Monk,
조종사들과 지구 주위를
돌고 있었단 말입니다
circling the Earth with my crew.
왜 그렇게 만족하질 못하는 겁니까?
Why doesn't that satisfy?
내가 신경 쓰이나요?
Am I making you nervous?
전혀요
Never.
왠지 아십니까?
You know why?
봤죠? 겁먹었잖아요
See? You flinched.
당신은 겁쟁이입니다
See, you're a flincher.
절대 나를 방해하진 못할 겁니다
You'll never stop me
왜냐하면 정작
결정적인 순간이 다가오면
because when the chips
are down when it really counts,
당신은 항상 그렇게
겁을 먹을 테니까요
you are always going to flinch.
방해해서 죄송합니다
가셔야 해요
Sir, sorry to interrupt.
We have to go.
실례해도 될까요?
주지사님이 기다리고 계셔서요
Would you excuse us?
The governor's waiting.
세상에. 몽크 씨가 맞았어요
My god. You were right.
저 사람이 죽인 거예요
He killed her.
거의 자백이나 마찬가지였잖아요
That was almost a confession.
하지만 어떻게 한 거죠?
But how?
어떻게 죽인 거냐고요?
How did he do it?
그냥 장난감일 뿐이었어요
조그만 빨간색 손전등이었죠
And they were just toys.
Little red flashlights.
그런데 전 정말 무서웠어요
But I was terrified.
소리 지르고 싶었습니다
I wanted to scream.
그래서 어떻게 했죠?
What, what did you do?
소리 질렀죠
I screamed.
비명 소리를 들었는데
제가 낸 게 확실하더군요
At least I heard screaming.
Pretty sure it was me.
에이드리안, 많은 사람들 앞에서
강연을 하셨다니
Adrian, you were giving a speech
in front of a group of people.
정말 발전하신 거예요
That's real progress.
아뇨, 정말 자랑스럽습니다
No, really. I'm very proud of you.
그렇군요
Yeah.
두려움을 완전히
없애는 것은 불가능할 거예요
You're never going to be
completely free of fear.
그걸 기대하시면 안 돼요
You can't expect that.
하지만 진정한 용기는 두려움을
극복하고 그걸 해내는 겁니다
But real courage is being afraid
of something and doing it anyway.
맙소사 / 왜요?
Nah. / What?
스티브 와그너도 그렇게 똑같이 말했죠
Steve Wagner said
the exact same thing.
그래요?
Really?
그 우주 비행사 말이죠
The astronaut.
박사님, 그 사람은
자기 여자 친구를 죽였어요
Doctor, killed his girlfriend.
그건 용서할 수 없죠
변론의 여지도 없습니다
Which I do not condone.
It's indefensible, of course.
전 항상 겁을 먹는 것 같아요
Seems I'm afraid all the time.
겁을 먹는 것도 이젠 지쳤습니다
I'm so tired of being afraid.
에이드리안, 당신의
공포증에 대해 얘기하고 싶군요
Adrian. I'm anxious to
talk about your phobias.
우리 '혐오 치료법'에 대해서 얘기했었죠
We talked about aversion therapy.
아, 그래요
Now, okay.
자, 자, 하죠
어서 하자고요
Let's, let's, let's do it.
Let's do it right now.
- 알았어요, 좋아요
- 시작하죠
- Okay. Okay. All right.
- Here we go.
그러죠. 어떤 공포를 먼저 시작할까요?
All right. Which of your fears
would you like to work on first?
- 빙하요
- Glaciers.
아뇨
No.
로데오요
Rodeos.
아니, 빙하요. 빙하
Ah, glaciers. Glaciers.
좋아요. 근본적인 공포부터
시작해 보는 게 어떨까요?
All right, why don't we just
start with a basic one?
- 고소 공포증 어때요?
- 맞아요, 고소 공포증
- Fear of heights.
- Okay. Heights.
- 그래요
- 좋습니다
- Heights.
- Let's do it.
자, 바로 지붕으로 올라갑시다
Okay, good.
Let's get up on the roof right now.
기다려요. 잠깐, 잠깐만요
잠깐 앉아 보세요
Wait. Whoa. Okay. Wait, wait.
All right, wait, sit.
- 앉죠
- 앉으세요
- I'll sit.
- Sit down.
됐어요, 앉았습니다
Okay, I'm down. Sitting down.
제가 준비가 안 됐어요
Not, I'm not ready.
직접 가는 건요
For that.
차차 발전시켜 보자고요
Let's, let's just build up to it gradually.
이렇게 하죠
Here's what.
그냥 여기 앉아서
Why don't we sit here and, uh,
정말 높은 건물의 이름을 대는 겁니다
name really tall things.
제가 먼저 하죠
I'll go first.
시어스 타워
The Sears tower.
아, 잠깐, 잠깐만요
Okay, wait, wait, wait.
그건 너무 높군요
No. That's too tall.
음, 시어스 타워 말고요
Um, not the Sears tower.
그냥 평범한 시어스 건물로 하죠
Just a regular Sears maybe.
평범한 시어스 건물...
백화점으로 하죠
Just a regular Sears.
Department store.
에이드리안, 공포증에 대해서는
다음에 하는 게 어떨까요?
Adrian, why don't we work
on your phobias another time, okay?
좋습니다
Okay.
그러니까...
When I...
스티브 와그너 같은
진짜 남자를 보면 말이죠
when I look at a man,
a real man like Steve Wagner...
제가 나약하다는 걸 느낍니다
I just feel weak.
제가 부족한 사람이란 걸 느껴요
I just feel so inadequate.
그 사람이 범인이란 건 알지만
I know he's guilty.
그걸 증명해낼 순 없을 거예요
But I'll never be able to prove it.
에이드리안, 스티브 와그너도 인간입니다
Adrian, Steve Wagner is a human being.
죄를 지은 게 맞다면, 분명
몹시 두려워하는 게 있을 겁니다
And if he's guilty, I know something
he's very much afraid of.
그게 뭐죠?
What's that?
당신이죠
You.
조앤은 집에 있었고
She's in the house.
와그너는 저 우주에 있었어요
He was up there in space.
지구 주위를 돌면서요
Circling the Earth.
- 공범자가 있었는지도 몰라요
- 아니에요
- Maybe he had an accomplice.
- No.
이웃 사람들 진술은 다 들었잖아요
We have statements from
all of the neighbors.
찾아온 사람도 없었고
차도 없었어요
There were no visitors, no cars.
조앤은 확실히 혼자 있었다고요
She was definitely alone.
어떻게든 와그너가 지구 밖에서
조앤을 죽였을 거예요
Somehow he killed her from up there.
와, 인형을 많이 모았네요
Well, she collected a lot of dolls.
정말 다들 못생긴 인형들이군요
Lot of really ugly dolls.
나탈리, 구멍이에요
Natalie. Holes.
어떻게 저걸 놓칠 수 있지?
How did we miss that?
최근에 뚫린 구멍이에요
They were drilled recently.
그래서요? 조앤이 저 밖에서 살해당한 건
아니잖아요. 여기서 죽었지
So? She wasn't killed out there.
She was killed in here.
발견된 장소는 여기지만
She was found in there.
다른 곳에서 살해됐을 수도 있어요
She could've been killed
someplace else.
호랑이도 제 말 하면 온다더니
Speak of the devil.
미안합니다. 누가 있었는지는 몰랐네요
Sorry. I didn't know anyone was here.
뭘 찾고 계신가 보네요?
Are you looking for something?
정원에 있는 꽃들을 가져가려고요
I wanted a flower from her garden.
조앤은 이 정원을 좋아했죠
She loved this garden.
나도 조앤을 좋아했습니다
그걸 부정하진 않겠어요
I cared for the girl.
I won't deny that.
꽃 하나 가지러 먼 길을 오셨네요
You came a long way to pick a flower.
사실, 이쪽으로 올 일이 있었어요
Actually, I was heading up here anyway.
두 시간 후에 팩스톤에서
시험 비행이 있거든요
I have a test flight
at Paxton in a couple of hours.
이제 그쪽 차례입니다
여긴 뭐 하러 오신 거죠?
Now it's your turn.
What are you doing here?
조앤의 살인 사건을
수사하고 있었습니다
I'm investigating Joanne's murder.
- 자살이죠
- 타살이었어요
- Her suicide.
- It was murder.
우리 둘 다 그건 알 거라 생각되는데요
I think we both know that.
왜 이래, 이 녀석아
너 귀머거리냐?
Come on, man. Are you deaf?
차고 문 좀 닫고 다니란 말이다
Please, just close the damn garage door.
세 번이나 닫았다고요!
Well, I did three times!
뭐? 봐라
또 열려 있잖아
Well, guess what?
It's open again.
- 고장 났나 보죠
- 아니야. 이건 새거라고
- Maybe it's broke.
- It ain't broke. It's brand-new.
세상에, 저길 봐
Holy son of a, look at this.
저 남자 좀 봐라
꼭 그 사람 같은데...
Look at him.
He looks just like...
- 누군지 알 것 같다
- 누군데요?
Hey, you know what,
I think that is. / Who?
그 사람 말이야!
그... 그 남자
The, who?
The, he's the, the guy.
TV에 나온 그 우주 비행사
유명한 사람 말이야
The spaceman from TV.
He's famous.
카메라 좀 가져와
넌 오빠랑 같이 있거라
Go get the camera would you?
Get the, get the, stay with your brother.
카메라 가져와
Go get the camera.
어, 잠시만요. 실례합니다
Uh, excuse me. Excuse me.
어, 어... 실례해요
당신 유명한 사람 맞죠?
Uh, uh, uh, excuse me.
Uh, you, you're famous, right?
- 스티브 욜란스키였던가...
- 와그너요. 스티븐 와그너입니다
- You're that Steve Wolanski...
- Wagner. Steven Wagner.
와그너. 그럴 줄 알았어요
와그너 씨
Wagner. I knew that.
Wagner.
우주 비행사 맞죠?
You're the space cowboy, right?
오, 세상에. 우주선에 불이 났을 때
비상 착륙 시켰던 그 사람이잖아요
Oh, man, you're, you're the dude that
landed the space shuttle when it was on fire.
맞습니다
That's correct.
- 그것 때문에 10달러를 잃었어요
- 실망시켜 드려서 죄송하군요
- I lost ten bucks on that.
- Sorry to disappoint you.
실례해도 될까요?
뭘 좀 하고 있어서요
Would you excuse us?
We're in the middle of something.
죄송하지만 가 주실래요?
Could you excuse us, please?
길 건너에 살고 계시죠. 맞죠?
You folks live across the street.
Is that, right?
네? 맞아요. 저기가 우리 집이에요
Huh? Yeah. It's us right over here.
네, 맞습니다
안녕하세요?
Yeah, that's right,
how are you, man?
만나서 반가워요. 전 대럴입니다
Good to meet you. I'm Darrel.
- 얘는 제 딸 도나고 이 녀석은...
- 만나서 반가워요
This is my daughter Donna here
and this is, uh... / Hi, nice to meet you.
- 베니입니다
- 여기서 뭐 하시는 거죠?
Benny. / What the hell
are you doing here?
호기심이 많은 아이구나. 그렇지?
You're curious, aren't you?
남자 애가 가질 최고의 덕목이
바로 호기심이지
That's the best thing a boy can have.
Curiosity.
난 여기에 살았던 여자 분의 친구란다
I was friends
with the lady that lived here.
오, 이런. 정말 유감이에요
정말...
Oh, man. That's a shame.
That's...
충격적인 사건이었죠
that's heart breaking.
- 사진 좀 찍어도 될까요?
- 더 좋은 걸 해 드리죠
- Can we get a picture?
- I can do better than that.
두 시간 후에 신형 제트기의
시험 비행이 있어요
I'm flight testing a brand-new jet
in a couple of hours.
오셔서 구경하실래요?
How'd you like to come and watch?
가족 분들을 전부 데리고 오세요
그렇게 하시죠
Bring the whole family.
Be my guests.
네? 농담하시는 거죠?
괜찮겠어요?
What, are you, you kidding me?
They wouldn't mind?
당연히 괜찮고말고요
세금을 내고 계시잖아요?
You have every right to be there.
You're a tax payer, right?
네
Yeah.
- 판매세지만요
- 저희도 가도 될까요?
- Sales tax.
- Could we come too?
전 열렬한 비행기 팬이거든요
I'm a big aviation buff, fan.
맞아요. 광팬이시죠
That's so true.
Such a fanatic.
- 난 비행기를 사랑해요
- 아주 사족을 못 쓰시죠
- I love airplanes.
- Just crazy about the, uh...
- 아무리 봐도 질리지가 않아요
- 이륙하는 걸 보시면요
- Can't get enough of them.
- The takeoff.
날개도 좋고 다 좋아요
And the wings and all.
- 방향타도 좋아요
- 그리고 착륙도 좋아하세요
- There we go. The rudder.
- And that, the landing.
우리도 가도 괜찮으시겠죠?
You wouldn't mind if we come to you.
- 팩스턴 공군 기지 -
최신 기술의 집대성이라고 할 수 있죠
Talking about state-of-the-art
technology here.
지금까지 만들어진 것 중
가장 진보한 전투기입니다
The most advanced
war planes ever built.
몇몇 비행기는 시제품입니다
Some of these planes are prototypes.
아직 그 비행기를 타고
날아본 사람은 없다는 뜻이죠
That means nobody's ever flown them.
- 위험할 것 같은데요
- 위험할 수도 있죠
- Sounds dangerous.
- It can be dangerous.
그런데 왜 하시는 거죠?
Then why do you do it?
내가 하지 않으면
다른 사람이 할 테니까, 베니
If I didn't do it, Benny,
somebody else would.
그럼 재미가 없잖아
Where's the fun in that?
애들이 좋아할 만한 게 나왔군요
비행 시뮬레이터죠
Now you kids will love this.
This is a flight simulator.
- 3천만 달러짜리 비디오 게임이랄까요
- 멋져요
- It's kind of like a $30 million video game.
- Cool.
- 보고 싶니?
- 네
- Want to check it out?
- Okay.
어른들은 여기 계세요
금방 돌아오겠습니다
You grown-ups stay here.
We'll be right back.
사보 대위, 이분들을 부탁하네
Captain Savo, you're in charge.
정말 좋은 사람이네요
He is good people.
네. 좋은 사람이죠
Yeah. He is good people.
저 사람을 잘 아세요?
Hey, how well do you know him?
뭔가 꿍꿍이가 있다는 건 압니다
Well enough to wonder
what he's doing.
안으로 들어가죠
Let's go in.
이런, 이런...
거긴 좀 어두운데요
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa.
That's a little dark in there.
밖에서 잠시 기다리죠
Let's just wait out here for awhile.
폴리!
Paulie!
차고 문이 왜 열려 있는 건가?
Why is this garage door open?
모르겠습니다, 상병님
저절로 열렸습니다
Don't know, serge.
Opened by itself.
시공을 잘못 했나 봅니다
Maybe we installed it wrong.
우리 집에도 같은 문제가 있었는데
전염병 같은 건가 보군요
I got the same problem with my garage.
It's like an epidemic.
나탈리, 어떻게 했는지 알겠어요
Natalie, I know how he did it.
어떻게 조앤을 죽였는지 알겠다고요!
I know how he killed her!
차고 문이 바로 답이에요
It's all about the garage doors.
그래요? / 네!
It is? / Yes!
- 아빠 / 아빠!
- 와그너 씨는 어디 있니?
- Dad. / Daddy!
- Where's Mr. Wagner?
갔어요. 뭔가에 늦었다고 하면서요
He left. He said
he was late for something.
- 왜 그러니, 아가?
- 그 아저씨가 얘 인형을 가져갔어요
- What's wrong, sweetie?
- The astronaut took her doll.
- 인형을 가져갔다고?
- 그거예요!
- He took her doll?
- That's it!
나탈리, 인형이 바로 답이에요!
Natalie, it's all about the doll!
아깐 차고 문이 답이라면서요?
You just said it was all
about the garage door.
인형과 차고 문이 답이에요
It's about the doll and the garage door.
둘 다라고요
It's about both.
케인 씨, 그 인형 어디에서 났죠?
Mr. Cain, where did you get that doll?
- 그게...
- 어서요. 훔친 거 맞죠?
I... / Come on.
You stole it, didn't you?
조앤의 현관문 앞에 있던
상자 안에 있던 겁니다
It was in a box sitting
on Joanne's front porch.
과일 상자를 가져간 것처럼
그 상자를 가져간 거예요
And you took it just like you took
the fruit of month box.
3일 동안이나 거기에
있었단 말입니다. 알겠어요?
It was sitting there
for three days, all right?
- 조앤이 집에 없다고 생각했고요
- 정말 끔찍한 이웃이로군요
- I figured she wasn't home.
- You're a horrible neighbor.
얘야, 괜찮을 거야
Honey, it's gonna be all right.
괜찮을 거야
It's gonna be okay.
괜찮아, 아가. 착하지
It's gonna be all right.
Sweetie, come on.
사보 대위입니다
방금 두 명의 민간인이 사라졌습니다
This is captain Savo.
I just lost two of my civilians.
헌병대에 알리십시오
Notify the law enforcement desk.
고마워요
경감님이 오신대요
Thank you.
The captain's on his way.
와그너가 그 인형을
없애기 전에 찾아야 해요
We have to find Wagner
before he gets rid of that doll.
몽크 씨, 전 이해가 안 되네요
Monk, I don't understand.
이렇게 된 거예요
Here's what happened.
와그너는 출항하기 전에
Before he left,
조앤의 집에 들렀던 게 틀림없어요
Wagner must've gone
to Joanne's house.
조앤에게 약을 먹였지만
죽을 만큼은 아니었죠
He drugged her
but not enough to kill her.
단지 며칠 동안 정신을
잃을 만큼만 먹인 거예요
Just enough to knock her out
for a couple of days.
그런 다음 와그너는
살인용 장치를 만들었어요
Then he built a machine,
a murder machine,
와그너가 떠난 한참 뒤 수요일에
조앤을 목매달아 죽일 장치를요
a machine that would hang her
on Wednesday long after he was gone.
- 무슨 장치요?
- 차고 문 개폐 장치요
- What kind of machine?
- A garage door opener.
와그너는 조앤을 약에 취하게 한 다음
목에 밧줄을 묶었을 거예요
He left her there drugged.
Probably tied up.
그리고 전 세계가 지켜보는 가운데
우주선을 타고 출항한 거죠
And then took off into space with
the whole world watching.
몽크 씨, 뭐 하는 거예요?
Mr. Monk, what are you doing?
나도 몰라요
I don't know.
2번 격납고 앞에 있다
남자는 미사일을 만지고 있다
They're at ramp two.
He's handling the missiles.
안 돼요, 안 돼
그거 미사일이래요
No, no, no, no.
Those are missiles.
핵무기일지도 몰라요!
They could be nuclear weapons!
그럼 제발 나 좀 말려 줘요!
Then stop me for the love of god.
이해가 안 돼요
조앤은 수요일에 죽었잖아요
I don't understand.
She died on Wednesday.
- 어떻게 그 장치를 작동시킨 거죠?
- 간단했죠. 영리했고요!
- How did he activate the machine?
- It was so simple, it was brilliant!
리모컨을 이용한 거예요
He used a remote control.
와그너는 리모컨을
켠 상태로 고정한 다음
He taped it or glued it down
so it stayed on.
그 인형들 중의 하나에
리모컨을 넣은 거예요
Then he put the remote control
inside one of those dolls.
그리고 이틀 후에 도착하도록
조앤의 집에 부친 거죠
Then he mailed it to her own house
second day mail.
이틀 후에 도착했으면
수요일 아침이군요?
Second day mail?
Wednesday morning.
맞아요. 시한폭탄 같은 거였죠
Exactly. It was like a time bomb.
우편배달부가 그 리모컨을
현관 앞에 배달하자
The mail man delivered the remote control,
put it on the front porch.
문 안쪽에서 조앤의 목이
매달리게 된 거예요
On the other side of that door,
she was being strangled.
맙소사
Oh, my god.
그런데 조앤은 거실에서 발견됐잖아요!
But they found her in the living room!
지구에 도착한 후
다시 조앤의 집으로 가서
After he landed,
Wagner went back to her house.
장치를 치우고 시체를
다른 방으로 옮긴 거예요
He dismantled the machine
and moved her body into the other room.
한 가지만 빼면 완벽한 계획이었어요
It was a perfect plan
except for one thing.
인형이 사라졌거든요
The doll was missing.
와그너는 몹시 당황했을 거예요
오늘 온 것도 그걸 찾기 위해서였죠
He must've panicked.
He went back there again today to find it.
그 리모컨 때문에 범행이
드러날 수 있다는 걸 안 거예요
He knew that remote could
tie him to the murder.
거기에 온통 지문이 묻어 있으니까요
잠시만요!
His fingerprints are all over it.
Excuse me!
- 저기요
- 이봐요, 비행기 멋진데요
Hi. / Hey, nice ride.
- 스티브 와그너 씨를 찾고 있거든요
- 비행 대기선에 있을 거예요
- Hi, We're looking for Steve Wagner.
- He may be on the flight line.
이륙 준비를 끝마쳤을 것 같은데요
I think they just cleared him for takeoff.
멋지군요. 우리도 보고 싶거든요
어느 쪽이죠?
Great. We'd love to watch.
Which way?
금방 찾을 수 있을 겁니다
최신 기종인 FA-22에 있거든요
You can't miss him.
He's in the brand-new FA-22.
아, 참
Uh, yeah. Yeah.
저기, 또 뵙는군요
Yeah, hi.
Hello, again.
이거 하나만 알려 주시겠어요?
제 친구와 제가 내기를 했는데요
Could you settle a bet?
My friend and I were wondering if, uh,
FA-22기 조종석에서 밖으로
물건을 떨어뜨릴 수 있을까요?
somebody could drop anything
out of the cockpit of an FA-22.
- 물론, 전 불가능하다고 했죠
- 당연히 가능하다니까요
- Of course, I say no way.
- Of course you can.
어떤 물건을요?
Like what?
- 저기... 일본 인형요
- 이만한 크기예요
- Uh, you know, a Japanese doll.
- About this big.
에어 로크가 있어요. 조명탄이나
비상 송신기를 떨어뜨릴 때 쓰죠
Well, there's an air lock. Like a chute
to drop flares and emergency transmitters.
신세 졌네요. 계속하세요
I owe you one. Go figure.
고마워요 / 믿을 수가 없군요
나탈리가 이겼네요
Thank you. / That's unbelievable.
You win that one.
잠깐만요
이봐요, 호위병은 어디 있습니까?
Wait a second.
Hey, where's your escort?
- 가요, 가!
- 이봐요, 어딜 가는 겁니까?
- Go, go, go!
- Hey, where you going?
안 돼, 안 돼요. 몽크 씨! 기다려요!
No, no, no, Mr. Monk! Wait!
멈춰요! 멈추라고요!
Wait up! Wait up!
어이!
Hey!
이봐!
세워!
Pull it over!
세우라니까!
손을 머리에 얹고
무릎을 꿇으세요
Put your hands on your head.
Get on your knees.
비행기에서 물러서십시오
Sir, step away from the jet.
Step away from the jet.
샌프란시스코 경찰입니다
San Francisco police department.
- 멈춰요! 우리 편입니다!
- 저 사람은 내 부하입니다
- Stop! They're friendly!
- That's my man out there.
무기를 거둬라
경계 해제
Pack your weapons.
Stand down.
다시 말한다. 무기를 거둬라
경계를 해제한다
I say again. Pack your weapons.
Stand down.
대위님, 그 물건은 제게 주십시오
Captain, please hand me the item.
그 인형요
인형을 제게 주십시오
The doll, sir.
Hand me the doll.
보안 팀, 용의자를 호송하도록
Security team, secure the suspect.
용의자를 도운 꼴이 됐군
이제 항공기를 돌려놓게
Helped the suspect.
Now secure the air craft.
본부, 용의자를 호송한다
Control, suspect secure.
어서, 줄리. 어서 가자
Come on. Julie. Come on.
몽크 씨, 줄리가 몽크 씨를 위해
뭘 만들었대요
Mr. Monk.
Julie made something for you.
그래? / 저희 학교 친구들 모두가
아저씨가 해내신 일과
What? / Well, all my friends at school
were talking about what you did
와그너 씨에 대해서 얼마나
잘못 생각했는지 얘기했어요
and how we were
so wrong about Mr. Wagner.
그리고 어떻게 붙잡았는지도요
And how you caught him.
어쨌든 아저씨께 드리려고
미술 시간에 이걸 만들었어요
Well, um, anyways,
I made you this in art class.
오, 줄리
Oh, Julie.
용맹 훈장이에요
It's a medal of valor.
우리 아빠를 빼곤 아저씨가
제가 아는 가장 용기 있는 분이거든요
'Cause you're the bravest man
I've ever known except for my father.
오, 예쁘기도 하지
카메라 가져올게요
Oh, sweetie.
I'm gonna get the camera.
그게...
Well, I...
줄리, 고맙다. 고맙구나
Julie, thank you.
I, um, thank you.
잠깐, 잠깐만
그거 뭐니? 핀이야?
Wait, wait a minute.
What is that? A pin?
- 네, 괜찮아요. 조심히 달게요
- 잠깐, 잠깐. 저기 말이다
- Yeah, it's okay. I'll be careful.
- Wait, wait. That, that, you know that.
피부가 찔릴 수 있어
사람이 감염된단다
That can puncture the skin.
People get infected.
그냥 잡고 있을게
그게 어떻겠니?
I'll just hold it.
How about that?
- 그게 좋을 거야
- 좋아요. 웃어요
- That's just as good.
- Okay. Smile.
- 람보 아저씨도 웃어요
- 잠깐만요. 여기 용기라고 적혀 있어요
- You too, Rambo.
- Wait, look. It says courage.
그래, 나도 보여
사진이나 찍자꾸나
Yeah. I see that. I see that.
Take, take the picture.
플래시는 터트리지 말아요
망막에 상처를 입을 수 있거든
No flash. No flash.
Retinal scarring.
자막제작 - NSC 자막팀
(http://club.nate.com/tsm)